https://canadaworldyouth.org/privacy-policy/

PRIVACY POLICY
Canada World Youth (CWY) is committed to protecting the privacy of confidential information provided by its stakeholders including; employees, volunteers, CWY Community members (past volunteers, past host families, past employees and Board members), donors, partners and all other stakeholders.
Confidential information can include, but is not limited to, records and personal information (ex: Social Insurance Numbers), banking information, budgets and financial information (with the exception of verified financial reports), the organization’s contact lists, including, among others, the list of current and past Board Directors, the list of host families, the donors list, information on past participants and current volunteers, as well as information on development projects or documents sent as a request for financial support to potential donors.Canada World Youth is committed to protecting the privacy of people whose personal information is held by the CWY through responsible information management. Any personal information provided to the CWY is collected, used and disclosed in accordance with applicable provincial and federal legislation regarding privacy and the protection of information and CWY policies on confidentiality and privacy.
Privacy Practices
The CWY collects and uses a limited amount of confidential information about its stakeholders. The information is used only for the purposes of processing volunteer applications and donations, keeping stakeholders informed about the activities of the organization, providing stakeholders with appropriate recognition and stewardship, and building support around its mission.
The CWY may also collect information from stakeholders regarding their interests and other related facts, in order to assist them in meeting their philanthropic goals through gifts and in-kind donations they make to the organization.
Confidential information collected is kept confidential, used for the purposes in which the confidential information was collected, and is only disclosed to meet the purposes stated above, unless expressly consented otherwise by alumni, volunteers, donor or stakeholder. All employees sign confidentiality agreements and safeguards are in place to ensure that the information is not accessed, disclosed or shared more widely than is necessary to achieve the purpose for which it was gathered.
CWY does not sell, rent or trade mailing lists or other personal information. To ensure that individual privacy is protected, we have instituted the following privacy policy following the Code of Ethics of the Canadian Marketing Association, the Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act (PIPEDA), notably the 10 privacy principles. In addition, CWY adheres to the Donor Bill of Rights as set out by Imagine Canada and additional standards of conduct as set out by the Association of Fundraising Professionals and the Canadian Association of Gift Planners.
Accountability: CWY is responsible for the confidential information it holds and uses for programming, fundraising and communication purposes.
Identifying Purpose: CWY collects, uses and discloses confidential information only for the purpose of processing volunteer applications, processing donations, keeping its stakeholders informed about the activities of the organization and building support around its mission.
Consent
CWY offers its stakeholders numerous privacy options, including the option to limit or opt out of future contact. Volunteers who apply to our programs, and donors who choose to contribute to CWY in response to a solicitation, give implied consent for their contact information to be used for that purpose. Any stakeholder may opt out of receiving future communications by contacting CWY.
Limiting Collection: Employees, volunteers or partners of CWY collect the information necessary for the purpose of a particular educational program, fundraising program, event or educational activity. The information will only be used for the purpose for which it was gathered. Other personal information may be gathered from stakeholders to assist with facilitating program applications, gifts, and other forms of support. Any information collected will be kept only as long as is required to serve the needs of the stakeholder.
Limiting Use, Disclosure and Retention: Safeguards are in place to ensure that information collected by CWY is not accessed, disclosed or shared inappropriately. Information is kept only as long as necessary for the original purpose for which it is collected, or to comply with Canada Revenue Agency guidelines.
Record Maintenance: CWY maintains complete and accurate confidential information as necessary for the taking part in programming, processing of donation receipts and the dispersal of fundraising, program or special event materials. Material recording personal information will be disposed of in a manner which ensures the security of personal information, i.e. document shredding.
Safeguarding Personal Information: CWY will protect stakeholder information on file by safeguarding access to this information. Only those who need access to the information to process applications, to issue receipts, to communicate information about the organization’s activities or to further the fundraising mission of the organization shall be provided with limited access. Personnel of the CWY agree to conduct their day-to-day business to ensure the confidentiality of each application, gift, request, inquiry or acknowledgement they are involved with.
Openness: The organization will provide stakeholders with the privacy policy through our website and upon request. A request can be sent to info@cwy-jcm.org or via telephone at 514-931-3526 or 1-800-605-3526 (toll free). All inquiries will be treated with the upmost respect and confidentiality.
Access: Individuals can request access to their confidential information and the organization will respond within 30 days to the request. Individuals have the right to ensure the information is accurate and complete and amend the file if necessary.
Challenging Compliance: Individuals can address complaints to Canada World Youth (CWY), 2330 Notre-Dame Street West, suite 300, Montreal, Quebec, H3J 1N4.
The complaint will be addressed within 60 days; after all involved parties have been interviewed. If the complaint is found to have validity, the process that drove the complaint shall be amended by the organization.
Privacy Policy
Whistleblower Policy
SAHE Policy
Contact Us
We respectfully acknowledge that you might be reading this from traditional and unceded territory.
©2020 Canada World Youth. All rights reserved.
×
